Cameron Leach

949.422.4800 | cameron.leach@gmail.com

Profile

Senior level manager of software applications engineering teams with qualities of a strong leader and can communicate effectively with technical and non-technical team members. A technical facilitator who makes teams better by establishing a culture focused on detailed and quality execution in a light and collaborative atmosphere. Has experience working on both small and large teams requiring the ability to stay organized and collaborative in fast-paced agile environments.

Experience

Disney Consumer Products and Interactive Media

Glendale, CA

Senior Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2017-Present

- Led large-scale initiative as the primary technical and project leader to move Disney Interactive's main web platform to Google Cloud, featuring ten major systems that support over 800 guestfacing sites, including Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com
- Technical lead of the connected consumer platform's application operations team, responsible
 for the performance and reliability of over 50 systems and tools, including content, data and
 asset management systems that support mobile app experiences like DisneyLife and Disney Gif
- Lead technical partner to platform solutions team, providing technical guidance and custom-built solutions tailored to the needs of customers and global content production teams
- Collaborates with platform leadership team on full-time and contingent workforce resource management to establish project teams that meet the needs of the organization within budget and on time

Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2014-Dec 2016

- Led product and engineering for backend content management and data platform, which powers Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com
- Responsible for backend engineering effort in the relaunch of starwars.com under the Disney banner for the first time
- Provides architectural and technical guidance on site-serving APIs and producer interface applications built with Ruby on Rails backed by MongoDB
- Managed revision of recommendation engine for Disney video portal that suggests related content through machine learning using Hadoop

Staff Software Engineer

Jan 2013-Dec 2013

- · Led front end and search engineering teams responsible for newly relaunched disney.com
- Migrated several legacy disney.com sites and portals onto search platform, including Disney Channel, Disney XD and Walt Disney Company corporate sites
- Launched internationalized front end sites and search platforms in Latin America and Europe, supporting multiple languages in a cohesive and integrated ecosystem

Senior Software Engineer

May 2011-Dec 2012

- Architected and built an entirely new search platform for the major relaunch of disney.com using open-source software and frameworks like Apache Solr and Spring
- Optimized primary search algorithm leading to an increase in direct affiliate revenue from search on disney.com over 500% year over year

- Search platform includes multiple scalable indices supporting varied clients through a common API including a producer-facing content management system backend as well as other frontfacing sites like disneybaby.com
- Spearheaded automation through continuous integration with Jenkins and Capistrano for scripted deployments
- Worked on a fast-paced agile Labs team whose purpose was to innovate on experimental features, many of which became the foundation for the new disney.com

CityGrid Media/Citysearch

West Hollywood, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2008-Apr 2011

- Led team of search engineers in deployment of new search functionality during major site redesign with algorithm improvements leading to increases in conversions and revenue of over \$500k per year
- Architected and scaled multiple clusters of Apache Solr-based indexes containing more than
 18 million unique business listings performing advanced geo-spatial local searches
- Responsible for development and deployment of CityGrid public content APIs serving localized business listing profiles, search, deals and user reviews used by more than 100 partners and developers
- Principal engineer on cross-functional scrum team responsible for building RESTful web applications for submission of user generated content including images, reviews and tweets from Twitter
- Built server-side component of auto complete/predictive text functionality using Apache Lucene with index containing over 3 million search terms localized to specific geographic regions
- Built self-enrollment wizard using Spring Webflow for backend customer system for new potential merchant signups

Warner Bros. Advanced Digital Services

Burbank, CA

Associate Application Engineer

May 2006-Apr 2008

- Led development of online video distribution applications for both client and server utilizing
 Java technologies and Windows DRM to generate cost savings of over \$1 million for studio
- Involved in development of several consumer facing Java applications including main portal,
 CRM application, and content management systems

Walt Disney TV Animation/DisneyToon Studios

Burbank, CA

Undergraduate Associate

Jun 2005-Aug 2005

- · Improved software scripts, increasing efficiency of the animation production pipeline
- · Provided assistance in production archival, system administration and technology upkeep

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

December 2005

- · Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- USC Presidential Scholar
- · USC SCion Scholar

Skills

Java (EE, SE)

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

Sinatra

 XML HTML

Apache Tomcat

Google Cloud Platform MongoDB

Google App Engine SQL Google Container Engine

Apache Solr

CSS

Lucene

Kubernetes Maven

Web Services/APIs

REST

Spring Framework

Hibernate

Docker

Helm

Continuous Integration

Mac OS X Unix/Linux

JavaScript